Kingsley Ofosu

kingsleyofosu@yahoo.com

+ [233] 201-694-902 / 541-424-292



www.linkedin.com/in/kingsleyofosu



www.kingsleyofosu.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a results-driven software developer with several years of experience in desktop and web applications development. I also have a strong background in database administration.

I am an expert in devising tailored solutions to assist businesses achieve their goals in a variety of industries and a cyber security enthusiast.

I strongly believe that, developing good applications for organizations always contribute to putting those organizations ahead. I am flexible enough to work in a team, but also enjoy working independently. I also possess superb communication skills.

SKILLS

- Frameworks and Languages -JavaScript, Node.js, Angular, Ionic, C#, VB.NET and SOL.
- Up to date knowledge of HTML5 and
- Web Technologies and Tools -Docker, Git, Jira, Confluence, **Jenkins**
- Version Control Github, Bitbucket
- Development Environments Microsoft Visual Studio and Visual Studio Code.
- Data Stores MS SQL Server, Oracle, MySQL and MongoDB.
- Operating Systems Windows, macOS and Linux.

- Troubleshooting computer hardware.
- Setting up, Configuring and troubleshooting of Basic LAN's.
- Installing and maintaining computer operating systems.
- Debugging and strong problemsolving skills.
- Setting up, Configuring and Installing of PC's and Printers.
- Sales and Marketing.
- **Financial Accounting**

EXPERIENCE

Vodafone Ghana

Accra, Ghana

Application Developer

March, 2020 - Present

ThinkWell Solutions Company Limited

Software Developer/Database Administrator

Sunyani – Bono Region, Ghana January, 2014 – May, 2019

- Designing, coding, debugging, testing and maintaining of Web/Desktop Applications.
- Designing, implementing and maintaining database for applications.
- Ensuring all applications meet the Software Requirement Specification.
- Testing applications developed by other development teams.
- Copyediting content for websites.
- Monitoring website and platform performance.
- Managing the hosting environment for websites and applications.
- Conducting training sessions for clients on the use of developed systems.

NATIONAL HEALTH INSURANCE SCHEME

Sunyani – Bono Region, Ghana September, 2013 – August, 2014

- National Service Personnel
- Educating potential members on the importance of the scheme.
- Registration of new members to the scheme.
- Entering membership data and generating temporary cards for members.
- Assist in vetting of claims submitted by the scheme's accredited health facilities.

EDUCATION

Catholic University College of Ghana

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Sunyani – Bono Region, Ghana September, 2009 – August, 2013

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Google Africa Developer Scholarship Program with Andela and Pluralsight

Mobile Web Specialist

May, 2019 – December, 2019

Pluralsight, Inc.

Used pluralsight.com, an amazing online education platform, to take courses offered by subject-matter experts, to acquire knowledge and skills in web development and cyber security.

 Developed a familiarity, solidified and enhanced my skills in JavaScript plus Node.js, Angular, HTML5 and CSS3.

- CompTIA Network+ courses Developed a familiarity with networking concepts, operations and procedures.
- CompTIA Security+ courses Developed a familiarity with how to install and configure systems to secure applications, networks and devices.
- Certified Information Systems Security Professional (CISSP) courses Acquired the foundational knowledge needed to effectively design and manage the security of an organization.

REFERENCES

DR. GYAASE PATRICK OHEMENG (DEAN)

FACULTY OF INFORMATION AND COMMUNICATION SCIENCES AND TECHNOLOGY CATHOLIC UNIVERSITY COLLEGE OF GHANA

kgyaase@gmail.com

Tel: +[233] 244-852-893 / 506-547-731

MR. ADORFUL FRANCIS (HEAD OF BUSINESS) THINKWELL SOLUTIONS COMPANY LIMITED

fr.andorful@gmail.com

Tel: + [233] 501-455-146